I'm a teacher and a practitioner
[AI] 我是一名教师和从业者
of civics in America.
[AI] 美国的公民学。
Now. I will kindly ask those of you who have just fallen asleep
[AI] 现在我将亲切地询问你们中那些刚刚入睡的人
to please wake up. (Laughter)
[AI] 请醒醒。（众笑）
Why is it that the very word "civics"
[AI] 为什么“公民”这个词
has such a soporific.  even a narcoleptic effect
[AI] 有这么一种催眠剂。甚至是发作性睡病
on us?
[AI] 在我们身上？
I think it's because the very  word signifies something
[AI] 我想这是因为这个词本身就意味着什么
exceedingly virtuous.  exceedingly important.
[AI] 非常善良的。非常重要。
and exceedingly boring.
[AI] 而且非常无聊。
Well. I think it's the responsibility of people like us.
[AI] 好我认为这是像我们这样的人的责任。
people who show up for gatherings like this
[AI] 参加这种聚会的人
in person or online. in any way we can.
[AI] 亲自或在线。无论如何我们都可以。
to make civics sexy again.
[AI] 让公民再次性感起来。
as sexy as it was during the American Revolution.
[AI] 和美国革命时期一样性感。
as sexy as it was during the Civil Rights Movement.
[AI] 和民权运动时一样性感。
And I believe the way we make civics sexy again
[AI] 我相信我们让公民再次性感的方式
is to make explicitly about the teaching of power.
[AI] 就是要明确关于权力的教导。
The way we do that. I believe.
[AI] 我们这样做的方式。我相信。
is at the level of the city.
[AI] 在城市层面上。
This is what I want to talk about today.
[AI] 这就是我今天想说的。
and I want to start by defining some terms
[AI] 我想从定义一些术语开始
and then I want to describe the scale
[AI] 然后我想描述一下规模
of the problem I think we face
[AI] 我认为我们面临的问题
and then suggest the ways that I believe cities
[AI] 然后提出我相信城市的方式
can be the seat of the solution.
[AI] 可以是解决方案的所在地。
So let me start with some definitions.
[AI] 让我从一些定义开始。
By civics. I simply mean the art
[AI] 通过公民。我只是指艺术
of being a pro-social. problem-solving contributor
[AI] 成为一个亲社会的人。解决问题的贡献者
in a self-governing community.
[AI] 在自治社区。
Civics is the art of citizenship.
[AI] 公民是公民的艺术。
what Bill Gates Sr. calls simply
[AI] 老比尔·盖茨所说的仅仅是
showing up for life.
[AI] 为了生活而出现。
and it encompasses three things:
[AI] 它包括三个方面：
a foundation of values.
[AI] 价值的基础。
an understanding of the systems that make the world go round.
[AI] 了解使世界运转的系统。
and a set of skills
[AI] 还有一套技能
that allow you to pursue goals
[AI] 让你去追求目标
and to have others join in that pursuit.
[AI] 并让其他人加入到这一追求中。
And that brings me to my definition of power.
[AI] 这就引出了我对权力的定义。
which is simply this:
[AI] 这很简单：
the capacity to make others do
[AI] 让别人做的能力
what you would have them do.
[AI] 你想让他们做什么。
It sounds menacing. doesn't it?
[AI] 听起来很危险。不是吗？
We don't like to talk about power.
[AI] 我们不喜欢谈论权力。
We find it scary. We find it somehow evil.
[AI] 我们觉得很可怕。我们觉得它有点邪恶。
We feel uncomfortable naming it.
[AI] 我们觉得给它命名很不舒服。
In the culture and mythology of democracy.
[AI] 在民主的文化和神话中。
power resides with the people.
[AI] 权力属于人民。
Period. End of story.
[AI] 时期故事结束了。
Any further inquiry not necessary
[AI] 没有必要进行进一步的调查
and not really that welcome.
[AI] 并不是那么受欢迎。
Power has a negative moral valence.
[AI] 权力具有消极的道德价值。
It sounds Machiavellian inherently.
[AI] 这听起来是马基雅维利式的。
It seems inherently evil.
[AI] 这似乎是天生的邪恶。
But in fact power is no more inherently good or evil
[AI] 但事实上，权力并不是天生的善或恶
than fire or physics.
[AI] 而不是火或物理。
It just is.
[AI] 就是这样。
And power governs
[AI] 权力支配一切
how any form of government operates.
[AI] 任何形式的政府如何运作。
whether a democracy or a dictatorship.
[AI] 无论是民主还是独裁。
And the problem we face today. here in America in particular.
[AI] 以及我们今天面临的问题。尤其是在美国。
but all around the world.
[AI] 但是在全世界。
is that far too many people  are profoundly illiterate
[AI] 太多的人是文盲
in power —
[AI] 当权-
what it is. who has it.
[AI] 这是什么。谁拥有它。
how it operates. how it flows.
[AI] 它是如何运作的。它是如何流动的。
what part of it is visible.  what part of it is not.
[AI] 它的哪一部分是可见的。它的哪一部分不是。
why some people have it.  why that's compounded.
[AI] 为什么有些人有它。为什么这是复杂的。
And as a result of this illiteracy.
[AI] 由于这种文盲。
those few who do understand
[AI] 那些少数真正理解的人
how power operates in civic life.
[AI] 权力如何在公民生活中运作。
those who understand
[AI] 明白的人
how a bill becomes a law. yes.
[AI] 法案如何成为法律。对
but also how a friendship  becomes a subsidy.
[AI] 还有友谊如何成为一种补贴。
or how a bias becomes a policy.
[AI] 或者偏见如何成为政策。
or how a slogan becomes a movement.
[AI] 或者一个口号如何成为一场运动。
the people who understand those things
[AI] 了解这些事情的人
wield disproportionate influence.
[AI] 拥有不成比例的影响力。
and they're perfectly happy
[AI] 他们非常开心
to fill the vacuum created by the ignorance
[AI] 填补无知造成的真空
of the great majority.
[AI] 绝大多数。
This is why it is so fundamental for us right now
[AI] 这就是为什么它现在对我们如此重要的原因
to grab hold of this idea of power
[AI] 抓住这种权力观念
and to democratize it.
[AI] 并使之民主化。
One of the things that is so profoundly exciting
[AI] 一件非常令人激动的事情
and challenging about this moment
[AI] 这一刻充满挑战
is that as a result of this power illiteracy
[AI] 这是权力文盲的结果吗
that is so pervasive.
[AI] 这是如此普遍。
there is a concentration
[AI] 有一种集中
of knowledge. of understanding. of clout.
[AI] 知识。理解力。影响力。
I mean. think about it:
[AI] 我是说。想想看：
How does a friendship become a subsidy?
[AI] 友谊如何成为一种补贴？
Seamlessly.
[AI] 天衣无缝。
when a senior government official decides
[AI] 当一位高级政府官员决定
to leave government and become a lobbyist
[AI] 离开政府成为说客
for a private interest
[AI] 为了私人利益
and convert his or her relationships into capital
[AI] 并将其关系转化为资本
for their new masters.
[AI] 为了他们的新主人。
How does a bias become a policy?
[AI] 偏见如何成为政策？
Insidiously. just the way that
[AI] 阴险地。就这样
stop-and-frisk. for instance.
[AI] 停下来搜身。例如。
became over time a bureaucratic numbers game.
[AI] 随着时间的推移，它变成了一场官僚主义的数字游戏。
How does a slogan become a movement?
[AI] 口号如何成为一场运动？
Virally. in the way that the Tea Party. for instance.
[AI] 病毒。以茶话会的方式。例如。
was able to take the "Don't Tread on Me" flag
[AI] 能够接受“不要踩我”的旗帜
from the American Revolution.
[AI] 来自美国革命。
or how. on the other side.
[AI] 或者如何。在另一边。
a band of activists could take a magazine headline.
[AI] 一群激进分子可以在杂志上刊登头条。
"Occupy Wall Street."
[AI] “占领华尔街。”
and turn that into a global meme and movement.
[AI] 并将其转化为全球性的模因和运动。
The thing is. though. most people
[AI] 事情是这样的。虽然大多数人
aren't looking for and don't want to see these realities.
[AI] 我们不想也不想看到这些现实。
So much of this ignorance. this civic illiteracy.
[AI] 如此多的无知。这是公民文盲。
is willful.
[AI] 他是任性的。
There are some millennials. for instance.
[AI] 有一些千禧一代。例如。
who think the whole business is just sordid.
[AI] 他们认为整件事都是肮脏的。
They don't want to have anything to do with politics.
[AI] 他们不想和政治有任何关系。
They'd rather just opt out
[AI] 他们宁愿选择退出
and engage in volunteerism.
[AI] 参与志愿服务。
There are some techies out there
[AI] 那里有一些技术人员
who believe that the cure-all
[AI] 谁相信万应灵药
for any power imbalance or power abuse
[AI] 任何权力失衡或权力滥用
is simply more data.
[AI] 只是更多的数据。
more transparency.
[AI] 提高透明度。
There are some on the left who think power resides
[AI] 有些左翼人士认为权力存在
only with corporations.
[AI] 只与公司合作。
and some on the right who think power
[AI] 还有一些右翼人士认为权力
resides only with government.
[AI] 只属于政府。
each side blinded by their selective outrage.
[AI] 双方都被选择性的愤怒蒙蔽了双眼。
There are the naive who believe that
[AI] 有些天真的人相信这一点
good things just happen
[AI] 好事就这样发生了
and the cynical who believe that bad things just happen.
[AI] 那些愤世嫉俗的人相信坏事就这么发生了。
the fortunate and unfortunate alike
[AI] 幸运的和不幸的都一样
who think that their lot is simply what they deserve
[AI] 他们认为自己的命运就是他们应得的
rather than the eminently alterable result
[AI] 而不是明显可变的结果
of a prior arrangement. an inherited allocation.
[AI] 事先安排好的。继承的分配。
of power.
[AI] 权力。
As a result of all of this creeping fatalism in public life.
[AI] 由于公共生活中的宿命论蔓延。
we here. particularly in America today.
[AI] 我们在这里。尤其是在今天的美国。
have depressingly low levels
[AI] 低得令人沮丧
of civic knowledge. civic engagement. participation.
[AI] 公民知识。公民参与。参加
awareness.
[AI] 知道
The whole business of politics has been
[AI] 政治的全部事务都已经结束了
effectively subcontracted out to a band of professionals.
[AI] 有效地分包给一批专业人士。
money people. outreach people.
[AI] 有钱人。外联人员。
message people. research people.
[AI] 给人们留言。研究人员。
The rest of us are meant to feel like amateurs
[AI] 我们其余的人注定会觉得自己是个业余爱好者
in the sense of suckers.
[AI] 在吸盘的意义上。
We become demotivated to learn more
[AI] 我们变得缺乏学习更多的动力
about how things work.
[AI] 关于事情是如何运作的。
We begin to opt out.
[AI] 我们开始选择退出。
Well. this problem. this challenge.
[AI] 好这个问题。这是一个挑战。
is a thing that we must now confront.
[AI] 这是我们现在必须面对的事情。
and I believe that when you have
[AI] 我相信当你
this kind of disengagement. this willful ignorance.
[AI] 这种脱离。这种故意的无知。
it becomes both a cause and a consequence
[AI] 它既是原因也是结果
of this concentration of opportunity
[AI] 这种机会的集中
of wealth and clout that I was describing a moment ago.
[AI] 我刚才描述的财富和影响力。
this profound civic inequality.
[AI] 这种严重的公民不平等。
This is why it is so important in our time right now
[AI] 这就是为什么它在我们这个时代如此重要的原因
to reimagine civics as the teaching of power.
[AI] 将公民学重新想象为权力的教学。
Perhaps it's never been more important
[AI] 也许这是前所未有的重要
at any time in our lifetimes.
[AI] 在我们有生之年的任何时候。
If people don't learn power.
[AI] 如果人们不学习权力。
people don't wake up.
[AI] 人们不会醒来。
and if they don't wake up.
[AI] 如果他们不醒过来。
they get left out.
[AI] 他们被排除在外。
Now. part of the art of practicing power
[AI] 现在练习权力的艺术的一部分
means being awake and having a voice.
[AI] 意思是保持清醒并发出声音。
but it also is about having an arena
[AI] 但这也是关于拥有一个竞技场
where you can plausibly practice deciding.
[AI] 在那里你可以合理地练习做决定。
All of civics boils down to the simple question
[AI] 所有的公民都归结为一个简单的问题
of who decides.
[AI] 由谁来决定。
and you have to play that out
[AI] 你必须把它演出来
in a place. in an arena.
[AI] 在一个地方。在竞技场上。
And this brings me to the third point that I want to make today.
[AI] 这就引出了我今天想说的第三点。
which is simply that there is no better arena
[AI] 也就是说，没有比这更好的竞技场了
in our time for the practicing of power
[AI] 在我们练习权力的时代
than the city.
[AI] 而不是城市。
Think about the city where you live.
[AI] 想想你居住的城市。
where you're from.
[AI] 你从哪里来。
Think about a problem in the common life of your city.
[AI] 想想你所在城市的日常生活中的一个问题。
It can be something small.
[AI] 它可以是一些小东西。
like where a street lamp should go.
[AI] 就像路灯应该去的地方。
or something medium like
[AI] 或者中等程度的
which library should have its hours extended or cut.
[AI] 哪个图书馆应该延长或缩短时间。
or maybe something bigger.
[AI] 或者更大的。
like whether a dilapidated waterfront should be
[AI] 比如一个破旧的海滨是否应该
turned into a highway or a greenway.
[AI] 变成高速公路或绿道。
or whether all the businesses in your town
[AI] 或者你镇上所有的生意
should be required to pay a living wage.
[AI] 应该被要求支付生活工资。
Think about the change that you want in your city.
[AI] 想想你想在你的城市里发生什么变化。
and then think about how you would get it.
[AI] 然后想想你将如何得到它。
how you would make it happen.
[AI] 你将如何让它发生。
Take an inventory of all the forms of power
[AI] 清点所有形式的权力
that are at play in your city's situation:
[AI] 在你所在城市的情况下起作用的：
money. of course. people. yes.
[AI] 钱当然人对
ideas. information. misinformation.
[AI] 思想。信息误传
the threat of force. the force of norms.
[AI] 武力威胁。规范的力量。
All of these form of power are at play.
[AI] 所有这些形式的权力都在发挥作用。
Now think about how you would activate
[AI] 现在想想你将如何激活
or perhaps neutralize these various forms of power.
[AI] 或者也许可以中和这些不同形式的权力。
This is not some Game of Thrones
[AI] 这不是什么权力游戏
empire-level set of questions.
[AI] 帝国级问题集。
These are questions that play out
[AI] 这些都是问题
in every single place on the planet.
[AI] 在地球上的每个地方。
I'll just tell you quickly about two stories
[AI] 我会很快告诉你两个故事
drawn from recent headlines.
[AI] 摘自最近的头条新闻。
In Boulder. Colorado.
[AI] 在博尔德。科罗拉多。
voters not too long ago approved a process
[AI] 不久前，选民们批准了一个程序
to replace the private power company.
[AI] 取代私营电力公司。
literally the power company. the electric company Xcel.
[AI] 实际上是电力公司。电力公司是Xcel。
with a publicly owned utility
[AI] 拥有一家公共事业公司
that would forego profits
[AI] 那将放弃利润
and attend far more to climate change.
[AI] 更多地关注气候变化。
Well. Xcel fought back.
[AI] 好Xcel进行了反击。
and Xcel has now put in play a ballot measure
[AI] Xcel现在已经开始实施投票措施
that would undermine or undo
[AI] 这将破坏或破坏
this municipalization.
[AI] 这是城市化。
And so the citizen activists in Boulder who have been pushing this
[AI] 波尔德的公民活动家们一直在推动这一计划
now literally have to fight the power
[AI] 现在，我们必须与权力作斗争
in order to fight for power.
[AI] 为了争夺权力。
In Tuscaloosa. at the University of Alabama.
[AI] 在塔斯卡卢萨。在阿拉巴马大学。
there's an organization on campus
[AI] 校园里有一个组织
called. kind of menacingly. the Machine.
[AI] 打电话。有点危险。机器。
and it draws from largely white sororities
[AI] 它主要来自于白人女生联谊会
and fraternities on campus.
[AI] 还有校园里的兄弟会。
and for decades. the Machine has dominated
[AI] 几十年来。这台机器占主导地位
student government elections.
[AI] 学生会选举。
Well now. recently. the Machine
[AI] 好吧，现在。不久前机器
has started to get involved
[AI] 已经开始介入
in actual city politics.
[AI] 在实际的城市政治中。
and they've engineered the election
[AI] 他们策划了选举
of a former Machine member.
[AI] 指以前的机器成员。
a young. pro-business recent graduate
[AI] 年轻人。专业商务应届毕业生
to the Tuscaloosa city school board.
[AI] 托斯卡卢萨市学校董事会。
Now. as I say. these are just two examples
[AI] 现在正如我所说。这只是两个例子
drawn almost at random from the headlines.
[AI] 几乎是从标题上随机抽取的。
Every day. there are thousands more like them.
[AI] 每一天还有成千上万的人像他们一样。
And you may like or dislike
[AI] 你可能喜欢也可能不喜欢
the efforts I'm describing here
[AI] 我在这里描述的努力
in Boulder or in Tuscaloosa.
[AI] 在博尔德或塔斯卡卢萨。
but you cannot help but admire
[AI] 但你不得不佩服
the power literacy of the players involved.
[AI] 参与者的权力素养。
their skill.
[AI] 他们的技能。
You cannot help but reckon with and recognize
[AI] 你不能不考虑和承认
the command they have
[AI] 他们的命令
of the elemental questions
[AI] 最基本的问题
of civic power —
[AI] 论公民权力-
what objective. what strategy. what tactics.
[AI] 什么目标。什么策略。什么战术。
what is the terrain. who are your enemies.
[AI] 地形是什么。谁是你的敌人。
who are your allies?
[AI] 谁是你的盟友？
Now I want you to return
[AI] 现在我要你回来
to thinking about that problem or that opportunity
[AI] 去思考那个问题或那个机会
or that challenge in your city.
[AI] 或者你所在城市的挑战。
and the thing it was that you want to fix
[AI] 那就是你想解决的问题
or create in your city.
[AI] 或者在你的城市里创造。
and ask yourself.
[AI] 问问你自己。
do you have command of these elemental questions of power?
[AI] 你掌握了这些基本的权力问题吗？
Could you put into practice effectively
[AI] 你能有效地付诸实践吗
what it is that you know?
[AI] 你知道的是什么？
This is the challenge and the opportunity for us.
[AI] 这是我们面临的挑战和机遇。
We live in a time right now
[AI] 我们现在生活在一个时代
where in spite of globalization
[AI] 尽管全球化在哪里
or perhaps because of globalization.
[AI] 或许是因为全球化。
all citizenship is ever more resonantly.
[AI] 所有公民身份都更加和谐。
powerfully local.
[AI] 强烈的地方性。
Indeed. power in our time is flowing
[AI] 的确我们时代的力量在流动
ever faster to the city.
[AI] 更快地到达城市。
Here in the United States. the national government
[AI] 在美国这里。国民政府
has tied itself up in partisan knots.
[AI] 陷入了党派纷争。
Civic imagination and innovation and creativity
[AI] 公民想象力与创新创造
are emerging from local ecosystems now
[AI] 正在从当地生态系统中崛起
and radiating outward.
[AI] 并向外辐射。
and this great innovation.
[AI] 这是一个伟大的创新。
this great wave
[AI] 这波巨浪
of localism that's now arriving.
[AI] 现在正在到来的地方主义。
and you see it in how people eat
[AI] 你可以从人们的饮食习惯中看出这一点
and work and share and buy and move
[AI] 工作、分享、购买和搬家
and live their everyday lives.
[AI] 过着他们的日常生活。
this isn't some precious parochialism.
[AI] 这不是什么宝贵的狭隘主义。
this isn't some retreat into insularity. no.
[AI] 这并不是什么孤岛化的退路。不
This is emergent.
[AI] 这是紧急情况。
The localism of our time is networked powerfully.
[AI] 我们这个时代的地方主义是强有力的网络化。
And so. for instance.
[AI] 等等。例如。
consider the ways that strategies
[AI] 考虑策略的方法
for making cities more bike-friendly
[AI] 让城市更加自行车友好
have spread so rapidly from Copenhagen
[AI] 从哥本哈根迅速蔓延开来
to New York to Austin to Boston to Seattle.
[AI] 从纽约到奥斯汀，从波士顿到西雅图。
Think about how experiments in participatory budgeting.
[AI] 想想如何在参与式预算中进行实验。
where everyday citizens get a chance
[AI] 普通公民都有机会
to allocate and decide upon
[AI] 分配和决定
the allocation of city funds.
[AI] 城市资金的分配。
Those experiments have spread from Porto Alegre. Brazil
[AI] 这些实验已经从阿雷格里港传播开来。巴西
to here in New York City.  to the wards of Chicago.
[AI] 到纽约这里来。去芝加哥的病房。
Migrant workers from Rome to Los Angeles
[AI] 从罗马到洛杉矶的移民工人
and many cities between
[AI] 和许多城市之间
are now organizing to stage strikes
[AI] 他们正在组织罢工
to remind the people who live in their cities
[AI] 提醒城市里的人们
what a day without immigrants would look like.
[AI] 没有移民的日子会是什么样子。
In China. all across that country.
[AI] 在中国。整个国家。
members of the New Citizens' Movement
[AI] 新公民运动的成员
are beginning to activate and organize
[AI] 正在开始激活和组织
to fight official corruption and graft.
[AI] 打击官员腐败和贪污。
and they're drawing the ire of officials there.
[AI] 他们引起了那里官员的愤怒。
but they're also drawing the attention
[AI] 但它们也吸引了人们的注意
of anti-corruption activists all around the world.
[AI] 全世界的反腐败活动家。
In Seattle. where I'm from.
[AI] 在西雅图。我来自哪里。
we've become part of a great global array of cities
[AI] 我们已经成为全球众多城市的一部分
that are now working together
[AI] 他们现在正在一起工作
bypassing government altogether.
[AI] 完全绕过政府。
national government altogether.
[AI] 整个国家政府。
in order to try to meet the carbon reduction goals
[AI] 为了实现碳减排目标
of the Kyoto Protocol.
[AI] 《京都议定书》的执行情况。
All of these citizens. united.
[AI] 所有这些公民。团结一致。
are forming a web.
[AI] 正在形成一个网络。
a great archipelago of power
[AI] 强大的群岛
that allows us to bypass
[AI] 这样我们就可以绕过
brokenness and monopolies of control.
[AI] 控制权的破裂和垄断。
And our task now is to accelerate this work.
[AI] 我们现在的任务是加快这项工作。
Our task now is to bring more and more people
[AI] 我们现在的任务是带来越来越多的人
into the fold of this work.
[AI] 加入这项工作。
That's why my organization. Citizen University.
[AI] 这就是为什么我的组织。公民大学。
has undertaken a project now
[AI] 他现在承担了一个项目
to create an everyman's curriculum
[AI] 创建普通人的课程
in civic power.
[AI] 在公民权力方面。
And this curriculum starts with this triad
[AI] 这门课程是从这个三位一体开始的
that I described earlier of values.
[AI] 我在前面描述的价值观。
systems and skills.
[AI] 系统和技能。
And what I'd like to do is to invite all of you
[AI] 我想邀请你们所有人
to help create this curriculum
[AI] 帮助创建此课程
with the stories and the experiences
[AI] 与故事和经验
and the challenges that each of you lives and faces.
[AI] 以及你们每个人生活和面临的挑战。
to create something powerfully collective.
[AI] 创造一个强有力的集体。
And I want to invite you in particular to try
[AI] 我特别想请你试试
a simple exercise drawn
[AI] 一个简单的练习画
from the early frameworks of this curriculum.
[AI] 从本课程的早期框架。
I want you to write a narrative.
[AI] 我要你写一篇叙述。
a narrative from the future of your city.
[AI] 来自你们城市未来的叙述。
and you can date it. set it out one year from now.
[AI] 你可以和它约会。从现在起一年后开始。
five years from now. a decade from now.
[AI] 五年后。十年后。
a generation from now.
[AI] 从现在开始的一代人。
and write it as a case study looking back.
[AI] 并将其作为回顾的案例研究。
looking back at the change
[AI] 回顾变化
that you wanted in your city.
[AI] 你想要在你的城市。
looking back at the cause that you were championing.
[AI] 回顾你所支持的事业。
and describing the ways that that change
[AI] 并描述这种变化的方式
and that cause came. in fact. to succeed.
[AI] 这个原因来了。事实上成功。
Describe the values
[AI] 描述这些值
of your fellow citizens that you activated.
[AI] 你激活的你的同胞。
and the sense of moral purpose that you were able to stir.
[AI] 以及你能够激发的道德目标感。
Recount all the different ways
[AI] 叙述所有不同的方式
that you engaged the systems of government.
[AI] 你参与了政府系统。
of the marketplace.
[AI] 在市场上。
of social institutions. of faith organizations.
[AI] 社会机构的管理。宗教组织。
of the media.
[AI] 媒体的报道。
Catalog all the skills you had to deploy.
[AI] 列出你必须部署的所有技能。
how to negotiate. how to advocate.
[AI] 如何谈判。如何倡导。
how to frame issues.
[AI] 如何界定问题。
how to navigate diversity in conflict.
[AI] 如何在冲突中驾驭多样性。
all those skills that enabled you
[AI] 所有那些使你
to bring folks on board
[AI] 把人们带到船上
and to overcome resistance.
[AI] 克服阻力。
What you'll be doing when you write that narrative
[AI] 当你写叙述的时候你会做什么
is you'll be discovering how to read power.
[AI] 你将发现如何解读权力。
and in the process. how to write power.
[AI] 在这个过程中。如何写电源。
So share what you write.
[AI] 所以分享你写的东西。
do you what you write.
[AI] 你知道你写什么吗。
and then share what you do.
[AI] 然后分享你所做的。
I invite you to literally share
[AI] 我邀请你来分享
the narratives that you create
[AI] 你创造的故事
on our Facebook page for Citizen University.
[AI] 在我们公民大学的Facebook页面上。
But even beyond that. it's in the conversations
[AI] 但除此之外。在对话中
that we have today
[AI] 我们今天所拥有的
all around the world in the simultaneous gatherings
[AI] 在世界各地的同时集会
that are happening on this topic at this moment.
[AI] 在这个话题上正在发生的事情。
and to think about how we can become
[AI] 想想我们怎样才能成为
one another's teachers and students in power.
[AI] 彼此的老师和学生掌权。
If we do that. then together
[AI] 如果我们这样做。然后一起
we can make civics sexy again.
[AI] 我们可以让公民再次性感起来。
Together. we can democratize democracy
[AI] 在一起我们可以使民主民主化
and make it safe again for amateurs.
[AI] 让业余爱好者再次安全。
Together. we can create a great network of city
[AI] 在一起我们可以创造一个伟大的城市网络
that will be the most powerful collective laboratory
[AI] 这将是最强大的集体实验室
for self-government this planet has ever seen.
[AI] 为了这个星球上从未见过的自治。
We have the power to do that.
[AI] 我们有能力做到这一点。
Thank you very much.
[AI] 非常感谢你。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）